<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Anshuman Tiwari</title>
    <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Anshuman Tiwari</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Image Segmentation with Pytorch</title>
      <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I embarked on a captivating journey to explore the fascinating world of image segmentation. By diving deep into the segmentation dataset, I gained a comprehensive understanding of its intricacies and nuances. To facilitate seamless integration, I developed a custom dataset class specifically tailored for the image-mask dataset, enabling efficient data handling and processing. To enhance the dataset further, I harnessed the power of segmentation augmentation techniques using the Albumentations library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Visualizing the filters of a CNN</title>
      <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>During this captivating guided project, I delved into the world of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) and uncovered the mesmerizing artistry hidden within. Using the renowned VGG16 model, I embarked on a mission to visualize the diverse filters spanning across its layers. Through the power of TensorFlow and the gradient ascent algorithm, I unlocked the secrets behind image activation and brought forth stunning visual representations.
Working on this project has been an eye-opening experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Transfer Learning for Image Classification</title>
      <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Throughout this captivating hands-on project, I ventured into the realm of deep learning, specifically exploring the incredible concept of transfer learning. Join me as I recount my journey, where I trained a classification model to predict food types, igniting a spark of innovation within the food industry.
This project has been an exhilarating learning experience for me. From the very beginning, I was captivated by the challenges presented in understanding the problem statement and acquainting myself with the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Hyperparameter tuning with NNI</title>
      <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Join me on an intriguing deep learning adventure as we delve into the realm of hyperparameter tuning using Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Neural Network Intelligence (NNI) toolkit. In this project project, I explored the capabilities of NNI, a powerful AutoML toolkit designed to automate various aspects of machine learning.
Throughout this project, I delved into the fascinating world of hyperparameter tuning using NNI. Embracing the power of this open-source toolkit, created by Microsoft, I harnessed its capabilities to automate feature engineering, hyperparameter tuning, neural architecture search, and model compression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Understanding the Explainabale AI</title>
      <link>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anshumantiware.github.io/AnshumanTiwari/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my captivating world of deep learning, where I embarked on an extraordinary project focused on the realm of explainable AI. Throughout this hands-on endeavor, I delved into the intricacies of Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), Residual Blocks, and the fascinating technique known as Grad-CAM.
With a vision to detect the type of scenery in satellite images, I trained a deep learning model that combines the power of CNNs and Residual Blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
